We conventionally divide space
نقسم الفضاء تقليدياً
into private and public realms,
إلى مجال عام وخاص،
and we know these legal distinctions very well
ونحن نعرف جيدا هذه التمييزات القانونية
because we've become experts
لأننا قد أصبحنا خبراء
at protecting our private property and private space.
في حماية ممتلكاتنا الخاصة وفضائنا الخاص.
But we're less attuned
ولكننا أقل تفهما
to the nuances of the public.
للمعاني الدقيقة لما هو عام.
What translates generic public space into qualitative space?
ما الذي يترجم الفضاءالشامل العام إلى فضاء نوعي؟
I mean, this is something
أقصد، هذا أمر
that our studio has been working on
ظل الاستوديو الخاص بنا يعمل عليه
for the past decade.
طيلة العقد الماضي.
And we're doing this through some case studies.
ونحن نقوم بهذا من خلال بعض الحالات الدراسية.
A large chunk of our work
مجال كبير من عملنا
has been put into transforming
تم توجيهه نحو تحويل
this neglected industrial ruin
هذا الخراب الصناعي المهمل
into a viable post-industrial space
إلى مساحات قابلة للإحياء في فترة ما بعد الصناعة
that looks forward and backward
تنظر إلى الأمام والخلف
at the same time.
في الوقت نفسه.
has gone into making relevant
يتجه نحو خلق الصلة مع
a site that's grown out of sync with its time.
مكان نشأ في غير تزامن مع زمانه.
We've been working on democratizing Lincoln Center
لقد عملنا على دمقرطة مركز لينكولن
for a public that doesn't usually have $300
لجمهور لا يمتلك في اغلب الاوقات مبلغ 300 دولار
to spend on an opera ticket.
لينفقها على تذكرة أوبرا.
So we've been eating, drinking,
وبالتالي فنحن نأكل ونشرب
thinking, living public space
ونفكر ونعيش الفضاءات العامة
for quite a long time.
لوقت طويل جداً.
And it's taught us really one thing,
وقد علّمنا ذلك أمرا واحدا،
and that is to truly make good public space,
وهو أن نخلق أماكن عامة جيدة بحق،
you have to erase the distinctions
علينا أن نزيل الفوارق
between architecture, urbanism,
بين العمارة والتمدن
landscape, media design
والمنظر الطبيعي والتصميم الوسائطي
and so on.
وهكذا دواليك.
It really goes beyond distinction.
وهذا حقا يتجاوز الفوارق.
Now we're moving onto Washington, D.C.
ننتقل الآن إلى واشنطن العاصمة
and we're working on another transformation,
ونحن نعمل على تحويل آخر،
and that is for the existing Hirshhorn Museum
ويتعلق ذلك بمتحف هيرشورن القائم
that's sited
والمتمركز
on the most revered public space in America,
في أكثر مكان عام مبجل في أمريكا،
the National Mall.
الناشونال مول.
The Mall is a symbol
والمول هو رمز
of American democracy.
للديمقراطية الأمريكية.
And what's fantastic is that this symbol
وما هو رائع هو أن هذا الرمز
is not a thing, it's not an image,
ليس شيئا ولا صورة،
it's not an artifact,
وهو ليس أداة،
actually it's a space,
في الواقع هو فضاء،
and it's kind of just defined by a line of buildings
وهو محدد نوعا ما بخط بنايات
on either side.
على كل من جانبيه.
It's a space where citizens can voice their discontent
أنها مساحة حيث يمكن للمواطنين التعبير عن سخطهم
and show their power.
وإظهار قوتهم.
It's a place where pivotal moments in American history
وهو المكان الذي حصلت فيه لحظات محورية من التاريخ الأمريكي
And they're inscribed in there forever --
وهي منقوشة هناك للأبد --
like the march on Washington for jobs and freedom
مثل مسيرة واشنطن من أجل الوظائف والحرية
and the great speech that Martin Luther King gave there.
والخطاب العظيم الذي ألقاه مارتن لوثر كينغ هناك.
The Vietnam protests, the commemoration of all that died
واحتجاجات الفيتنام وإحياء ذكرى كل من مات
in the pandemic of AIDS,
جراء وباء الإيدز،
the march for women's reproductive rights,
,المسيرة التي اقيمت من أجل حقوق المرأة الإنجابية،
right up until almost the present.
وصولا إلى الحاضر تقريبا.
The Mall is the greatest civic stage
المول هو أعظم ساحة مدنيّة
in this country for dissent.
في هذا البلد للمعارضة.
And it's synonymous with free speech,
وهو مرادف لحرية التعبير،
even if you're not sure what it is that you have to say.
حتى إذا كنت غير متأكد مما عليك قوله.
It may just be a place for civic commiseration.
فإنه قد يكون مجرد مكان للرثاء المدني.
There is a huge disconnect, we believe,
نعتقد أن هناك فاصلا ضخما
between the communicative and discursive space of the Mall
بين الفضاء الخطابي والتواصلي للمول
and the museums that line it to either side.
والمتاحف التي تمتد على كل من جانبيه.
And that is that those museums are usually passive,
وهو أن هذه المتاحف هي في العادة سلبية،
they have passive relationships between the museum
لديها علاقات سلبية بين المتحف
as the presenter and the audience,
كمقدم العرض والجمهور،
as the receiver of information.
كمستقبلين للمعلومات.
And so you can see dinosaurs
وبالتالي يمكنكم أن تروا ديناصورات
and insects and collections of locomotives
وحشرات ومجموعات من القاطرات
and all of that,
وكل ذلك،
but you're really not involved;
ولكنكم لستم مشاركين حقا؛
you're being talked to.
تتم مخاطبتكم فقط.
When Richard Koshalek took over as director of the Hirshhorn
عندما تولى ريتشارد كوشاليك إدارة هيرشورن
in 2009,
سنة 2009،
he was determined to take advantage
كان عاقدا للعزم على الإستفادة
of the fact that this museum was sited
من حقيقة أن المتحف يتمركز
at the most unique place:
في مكان فريد من نوعه:
at the seat of power in the U.S.
في مقر السلطة في الولايات المتحدة.
And while art and politics
وفي حين أن الفن والسياسة
are inherently and implicitly together always and all the time,
هما معا طوال الوقت بشكل اصيل و ضمني
there could be some very special relationship
فقد تكون هناك علاقة ما فريدة للغاية
that could be forged here in its uniqueness.
يمكن أن تقام هنا بتميزها.
The question is, is it possible ultimately
والسؤال هو، هل من الممكن في النهاية
for art to insert itself
للفن أن يقحم نفسه
into the dialogue of national and world affairs?
في الحوار حول الشؤون القومية والدولية؟
And could the museum be an agent of cultural diplomacy?
وهل يمكن للمتحف أن يكون عميلا للدبلوماسية الثقافية؟
There are over 180 embassies in Washington D.C.
هناك ما يزيد على 180 سفارة في واشنطن العاصمة.
There are over 500 think tanks.
هناك ما يزيد على 500 اتجاه فكري.
There should be a way
ينبغي أن تكون هناك طريقة
of harnessing all of that intellectual and global energy
لتسخير جميع تلك الطاقات الفكرية والعالمية
into, and somehow through, the museum.
وبطريقة ما عبر و نحو، المتحف.
There should be some kind of brain trust.
ينبغي أن يكون هناك نوع من مبلوري الافكار.
So the Hirshhorn, as we began to think about it,
وبالتالي حين بدأنا نفكر في هيرشورن
and as we evolved the mission,
ونحن نطور مهمتنا،
with Richard and his team --
مع ريتشارد وفريقه --
it's really his life blood.
إنه حقا دم حياته.
But beyond exhibiting contemporary art,
لكن بعيدا عن عرض الفن المعاصر،
the Hirshhorn will become a public forum,
سيصبح متحف الهيرشورن منتدى عام،
a place of discourse
و مكانا لنقاش
for issues around arts,
القضايا التي تدور حول الفنون،
culture, politics and policy.
والثقافة والسياسة والتشريع.
It would have the global reach of the World Economic Forum.
سيكون له نفس الإشعاع الدولي للـ"المنتدى الاقتصادي العالمي".
It would have the interdisciplinarity of the TED Conference.
ستكون لديه تعددية تخصصات مثل مؤتمر تيد.
It would have the informality of the town square.
سيغلب عليه الطابع الغير رسمي للميدان.
And for this new initiative,
ومن أجل هذه المبادرة الجديدة،
the Hirshhorn would have to expand
سيتعين على متحف الهيرشورن أن يتوسع
or appropriate a site
أو ان يستحوذ على موقع
for a contemporary, deployable structure.
لمبنى معاصر وقابل للانتشار.
This is it. This is the Hirshhorn --
ها هو ذا. هذا هو متحف الهيرشورن --
so a 230-foot-diameter concrete doughnut
كعكة مجوفة من الخرسانة بقطر 230 قدما
designed in the early '70s
صممت في أوائل السبعينات
by Gordon Bunshaft.
بواسطة غوردون بونشافت.
It's hulking, it's silent,
إنها ضخمة وصامتة
it's cloistered, it's arrogant,
ومنعزلة ومتغطرسة
it's a design challenge.
إنها تحدٍ في التصميم .
Architects love to hate it.
يجعل المهندسين المعماريين يحبون كرهه.
One redeeming feature
سمة واحدة ايجابية فيها
is it's lifted up off the ground
الا وهي أنها ترتفع بعيداً عن الأرض
and it's got this void,
وانها امتلكت هذا الخلاء
and it's got an empty core
وفيها مركز فارغ
kind of in the spirit and that facade
كنوع من الروح وتلك الواجهة
very much corporate and federal style.
تشبه كثيرا نمط الشركات والمباني الفدرالية.
And around that space,
وحول ذلك الفضاء،
the ring is actually galleries.
حلقة من المعارض التي
Very, very difficult to mount shows in there.
من الصعب جدا إقامة العروض فيها.
When the Hirshhorn opened,
عندما افتتح متحف الهيرشورن،
Ada Louise Huxstable, the New York Times critic,
أدا لويز هوكسستابل، ناقدة من صحيفة النيويورك تايمز،
had some choice words:
كان لها بعض الكلمات المختارة:
"Neo-penitentiary modern."
"السجون الجديدة المعاصرة."
"A maimed monument and a maimed Mall
"نصب تذكاري مشوه ومول مشوه
for a maimed collection."
لمجموعة مشوهة."
Almost four decades later,
وبعد قرابة الأربعة عقود،
how will this building expand
كيف سيتم توسيع هذا المبنى
for a new progressive program?
لبرنامج تقدمي جديد؟
Where would it go?
إلى أين قد يذهب؟
It can't go in the Mall.
لا يمكن أن يتوسع باتجاه المول.
There is no space there.
حيث انه ليست هناك المساحة لذلك.
It can't go in the courtyard.
ولا يمكنه التوسع باتجاه الفناء.
It's already taken up by landscape and by sculptures.
فقد تم ملؤه بالمشاهد الطبيعية والمنحوتات.
Well there's always the hole.
حسنا، هناك دائما الفجوة.
But how could it take the space of that hole
ولكن كيف يمكن أخذ مساحة تلك الفجوة
and not be buried in it invisibly?
من دون أن يدفن و يختفي بداخلها ؟
How could it become iconic?
كيف يمكن أن تصبح أيقونية؟
And what language would it take?
وما هي اللغة التي سوف تتطلبها؟
The Hirshhorn sits among the Mall's monumental institutions.
يتربع متحف الهيرشورن بين المؤسسات التذكارية للمول.
Most are neoclassical, heavy and opaque,
معظمها نيوكلاسيكية وثقيلة وغير شفافة،
made of stone or concrete.
مصنوعة من الحجر أو الخرسانة.
And the question is,
والسؤال هو:
if one inhabits that space,
إذا كان أحد يقطن هذا الفضاء،
what is the material of the Mall?
ما هي المواد الملائمة للمول؟
It has to be different from the buildings there.
يتعين أن يكون مختلفاً عن المباني هناك.
It has to be something entirely different.
يتعين أن يكون شيئا مختلفاً تماما.
It has to be air.
يتعين أن يكون هواء.
In our imagination, it has to be light.
يجب أن يكون ضوء، في مخيلتنا
It has to be ephemeral. It has to be formless.
يجب أن يكون سريع الزوال. يجب أن يكون غير ذي شكل.
And it has to be free.
وينبغي أن يكون حرا.
(Video)
(فيديو)
So this is the big idea.
وبالتالي فهذه هي الفكرة الكبيرة.
It's a giant airbag.
إنها وسادة هوائية عملاقة.
The expansion takes the shape of its container
التوسع يأخذ شكل الحاوية الخاصة به
and it oozes out wherever it can --
ويتسرب خارجا كلما استطاع --
the top and sides.
في الأعلى ومن الجوانب.
But more poetically,
ولكن بشكل أكثر شاعرية،
we like to think of the structure
يحلو لنا أن نفكر في البنية
as inhaling the democratic air of the Mall,
على أنها استنشاق لهواء ديموقراطية المول،
bringing it into itself.
تحضره لذاته.
The before and the after.
ما قبل وما بعد.
It was dubbed "the bubble" by the press.
أطلقت عليها الصحافة اسم "الفقاعة".
That was the lounge.
تلك كانت الصالة.
It's basically one big volume of air
إنها في الأساس وحدة تخزين كبيرة من الهواء
that just oozes out in every direction.
تتسرب بدقة في كل اتجاه.
The membrane is translucent.
الغشاء شفاف.
It's made of silcon-coated glass fiber.
وهو مصنوع من الألياف الزجاجية المغلفة بطبقة سيلكون.
And it's inflated twice a year for one month at a time.
ويتم نفخه مرتين في السنة لمدة شهر كل مرة.
This is the view from the inside.
وهذا هو المنظر من الداخل.
So you might have been wondering
حسنا قد تكونون تتساءلون
how in the world
كيف استطعنا
did we get this approved by the federal government.
أن نحصل على الموافقة من طرف الحكومة الفيدرالية.
It had to be approved by actually two agencies.
وقد كانت تتطلب موافقة وكالتين في الواقع.
And one is there to preserve
وإحداها موجودة للحفاظ على
the dignity and sanctity of the Mall.
كرامة وحرمة المول.
I blush whenever I show this.
أحمر خجلا كلما عرضت هذا.
It is yours to interpret.
لكم حرية تفسيره.
But one thing I can say
ولكن أمر واحد يمكن أن أقوله
is that it's a combination
هو أنها مجموعة
of iconoclasm
من محطمات المؤسسات التقليدية
and adoration.
والتمجيد.
There was also some creative interpretation involved.
كان هناك أيضا بعض التفسيرات الإبداعية المنطوية.
The Congressional Buildings Act of 1910
القانون الصادر عام 1910 حول مباني الكونجرس
limits the height of buildings in D.C.
يحد من ارتفاع المباني في العاصمة.
to 130 feet,
إلى 130 قدما،
except for spires, towers, domes and minarets.
وباستثناء القمم المستدبة والأبراج والقباب والمآذن.
This pretty much exempts monuments of the church and state.
وهذا يعفي المعالم الأثرية للكنيسة والدولة.
And the bubble is 153 ft.
وارتفاع الفقاعة هو 153 قدما.
That's the Pantheon next to it.
ذاك هو البانتيون إلى جانبها.
It's about 1.2 million cubic feet of compressed air.
إنها مشكلة من حوالي 1.2 مليون قدم مكعب من الهواء المضغوط.
And so we argued it
وهكذا، فقد جادلنا حول
on the merits of being a dome.
الأسس الموضوعية لكونها قبة.
So there it is,
وبالتالي ها هي ذي،
very stately,
في غاية الفخامة،
among all the stately buildings in the Mall.
بين جميع المباني الفخمة في المول.
And while this Hirshhorn is not landmarked,
وعلى الرغم من أن متحف الهيرشورن لم يتم اعتباره معلما،
it's very, very historically sensitive.
فإنه في غاية الحساسية التاريخية.
And so we couldn't really touch its surfaces.
وبالتالي لم نستطع في الواقع لمس أسطحه.
We couldn't leave any traces behind.
لم يكن بإمكاننا ترك أي آثار خلفنا.
So we strained it from the edges,
وبالتالي فقد وترناه في الحواف،
and we held it by cables.
وثبتناه بالكابلات.
It's a study of some bondage techniques,
إنها دراسة لبعض تقنيات الربط،
which are actually very important
والتي هي في الواقع في غاية الأهمية
because it's hit by wind all the time.
لأنها تتعرض لهبوب الرياح طوال الوقت.
There's one permanent steel ring at the top,
وهناك حلقة ثابتة من الفولاذ في الأعلى،
There are also some restrictions
وهناك أيضا بعض القيود
about how much it could be lit.
حول مقدار الإضاءة التي يمكن أن تتوفر عليه.
It glows from within, it's translucent.
إنها تضيء من الداخل، وهي شفافة.
But it can't be more lit than the Capitol
ولكن لا يمكن أن تكون مضاءة أكثر من مبنى الكابيتول
or some of the monuments.
أو بعض من المعالم.
So it's down the hierarchy on lighting.
لذا فهي في أسفل سلم الإضاءة.
It's taken off the delivery truck.
يتم أخذها من شاحنة التوصيل.
It's hoisted.
يتم رفعها.
And then it's inflated
ومن ثم يتم نفخها
with this low-pressure air.
بهذا الهواء ذي الضغط المنخفض.
And then it's restrained with the cables.
وبعد ذلك يتم تقييدها بالكابلات.
This is a very strange moment
هذه لحظة غريبة جداً
where we were asked by the bureaucracy at the Mall
حيث سألنا بيروقراطيو المول
how much time would it take to install.
كم من الوقت تستغرق للتثبيت.
And we said, well the first erection would take one week.
فقلنا أن الانتصاب الأول سيستغرق أسبوعا واحداً.
And they really connected with that idea.
وقد ارتبطوا حقا بتلك الفكرة.
And then it was really easy all the way through.
وبالتالي كانت سهلة جدا طيلة فترة العمل.
So we didn't really have that many hurdles, I have to say,
وبالتالي يجب علي القول أننا لم نواجه عقبات كثيرة
with the government and all the authorities.
مع الحكومة وجميع السلطات.
But some of the toughest hurdles
ولكن بعض أصعب العقبات
have been the technical ones.
كانت تلك التقنية.
This is the warp and weft.
هذا الاعوجاج واللحمة.
This is a point cloud.
هذه السحابة النقطية.
There are extreme pressures.
هناك ضغوط عالية جدا.
This is a very, very unusual building
وهذا مبنى غير اعتيادي للغاية
in that there's no gravity load,
حيث ليس هناك وجود لحمولة الجاذبية،
but there's load in every direction.
ولكن هناك حمل في كل اتجاه.
And I'm just going to zip through these slides.
وسأقوم فقط بتسريع مروري خلال هذه الشرائح.
And this is the space in action.
ها هو الفراغ أثناء العمل.
So flexible interior for discussions,
فضاء داخلي مرن للمناقشات
just like this, but in the round --
تماما مثل هذا، ولكنه في كرويته --
luminous and reconfigurable.
مضيئ وقابل لإعادة التشكيل.
Could be used for anything,
يمكن استخدامه لأي شيء،
for performances, films,
للعروض أو الأفلام
for installations.
أو التثبيتات.
And the very first program
وأول برنامج
will be one of cultural dialogue and diplomacy
سيكون حوارا ثقافيا ودبلوماسيا
organized in partnership
منظما بشراكة
with the Council on Foreign Relations.
مع مجلس العلاقات الخارجية.
Form and content are together here.
الشكل والمضمون موجودان معا هنا.
The bubble is an anti-monument.
فقاعة في ذاتها مضادة لما هو معلمي.
The ideals of participatory democracy
المثل العليا للديمقراطية القائمة على المشاركة
are represented through suppleness
تتجسد من خلال المرونة
rather than rigidity.
بدلاً من الجمود.
Art and politics
الفن والسياسة
occupy an ambiguous site outside the museum walls,
تحتلان موقعا غامضا خارج جدران المتحف،
but inside of the museum's core,
ولكن داخل جوهر المتحف،
blending its air
تمزج جوه
with the democratic air of the Mall.
مع الجو الديموقراطي للمول.
And the bubble will inflate
وسوف تنتفخ الفقاعة
hopefully for the first time
للمرة الأولى على ما نأمل
at the end of 2013.
في نهاية سنة 2013.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.